Guide to the Calspan Corporation records,1945-1973.
Calspan Corporation records,1945-1973
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Calspan Corporation records, 1945-1973.
17-1-1567
Calspan Corporation.
7 cubic ft.
Litigation documents, reports, financial statements, minutes, correspondence, news releases, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes litigation documents concerning Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory in the matter of Attorney General Lefkowitz vs. Cornell University, EDP Technology, Inc., and Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory; papers of Trustee Robert W. Purcell concerning the Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory; annual reports; financial statements; Board of Directors minutes; minutes of stockholder meetings; general correspondence; reports; news releases; and other records of the Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, including Annual Reports (1952-61), News Bulletin (1963-67), "Perspective" (1957-67), and "Research Trend" (1953-68); and agreements between EDP Technology, Inc. and Cornell University. Also, Charles W. Lake's files on the Cornell Engineering College Council's relations with CAL.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Calspan Corporation specializes in such areas as avionics, aerodynamic and flight research, acoustics, defense and space systems, environmental and energy systems, electronic countermeasures, security systems, surface chemistry, automotive and highway safety, thermal research, and many other technical and scientific areas. Previously known as the Cornell Areonautical Laboratory, the name was changed to Calspan Corporation in 1972.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes litigation documents concerning Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory in the matter of Attorney General Lefkowitz vs. Cornell University, EDP Technology, Inc., and Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory; papers of Trustee Robert W. Purcell concerning the Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory; annual reports; financial statements; Board of Directors minutes; minutes of stockholder meetings; general correspondence; reports; news releases; and other records of the Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, including Annual Reports (1952-61), News Bulletin (1963-67), "Perspective" (1957-67), and "Research Trend" (1953-68); and agreements between EDP Technology, Inc. and Cornell University. Also, Charles W. Lake's files on the Cornell Engineering College Council's relations with CAL.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Calspan Corporation.; Lake, Charles W.; Purcell, Robert W.; Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory.; Cornell University.; Cornell University.Engineering College Council.; EDP Corporation.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of office of origin except for Box 3.
CONTAINER LIST
- File #1
  - Summons and Complaint, 1968-11-08 (Box 1)
  - Order to Show Cause, 1968-11-12 (Box 1)
  - Order to Show Cause, 1968-11-13 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Cross-Motion, 1968-11-22 (Box 1)
  - Demand for Bill of Particulars (Box 1)
  - Order to Show Cause, 1968-11-21 (Box 1)
  - Defendants' Memo in Opposition to Plaintiff's Motion for Preliminary Injunction and in Support of Defendants' Cross-Motion (Box 1)
  - Affidavit, P.B. Wald, in Opposition to Defendants' Cross-Motion, 1968-11-25 (Box 1)
  - Memo in Opposition to CAL Tech Staff to Appear Amicus Curiae, 1968-11-25 (Box 1)
  - Brief on Application for Preliminary Injunction, 1968-11-26 (Box 1)
  - Affidavits, Maurice Axelrad, NYSASDA, 1968-11-14; 1968-11-26 (Box 1)
- File #2
  - Defendants' Reply Memo in Opposition to Plaintiff's Motion for Preliminary Injunction, etc. (Box 1)
  - Proceedings, 1968-11-26 (Box 1)
  - AG's Brief on Application for Preliminary Injunction, 1968-11-27 (Box 1)
  - Order, 1968-11-15 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Entry, 1968-12-04 (Box 1)
  - Affidavit - Asst. A.G. Hazel and Ira Ross, 1968-12-05 (Box 1)
  - Reply Brief - A.G., 1968-12-05 (Box 1)
  - Reply Affidavit - N. Stamp, 1968-12 (Box 1)
  - Briefs (Amicus Curiae) of NYSASDA, 1968-12-09 (Box 1)
  - Memorandum - Justice Marshall, 1969-01-03 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Settlement - Order, 1969-01-07 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Settlement - Counter Order, 1969-01-10 (Box 1)
  - Order, 1969-01-21 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Entry, 1969-01-23 (Box 1)
  - Answer, 1969-02-04 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Taking Deposition - CAL, 1969-02-07 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Taking Deposition - CU, 1969-02-07 (Box 1)
  - Deposition of Neal Stamp, 1969-03-06 (Box 1)
- File #3
  - Deposition of A. Green, 1969-03-07 (Box 1)
  - Stipulation, 1969-04-09 (Box 1)
  - Stipulation, 1969-05-06 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Motion, 1969-07-30 (Box 1)
  - Memo in Support of Plaintiff's Motion to Vacate Defendants' Demand for Bill of Particulars, 1969-08-14 (Box 1)
  - Defendants' Memo in Opposition to Plaintiff's Motion to Vacate or Modify Defendants' Demand for a Bill of Particulars (Box 1)
  - Decision and Order, 1969-09-22 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Motion, 1969-10-03 (Box 1)
  - Verified Bill of Particulars (Box 1)
  - Notice of Motion to Intervene - CAL Tech. Staff, 1969-10-24 (Box 1)
  - Brief in Support of Motion to Intervene - CAL Tech. Staff (Box 1)
  - Examination before Trial - Arthur Adams, 1969-10-29 (Box 1)
  - Affidavit - H. Moffitt (CAL Tech Staff Intervention), 1969-10-31 (Box 1)
  - Defendants' Brief in Opposition to Intervention, 1969-11-03 (Box 1)
  - Reply Brief in Support of Motion to Intervene - CAL Tech. Staff (Box 1)
- File #4
  - Order, 1969-11-06 (Box 1)
  - Opinion of Justice Kronenburg Denying Motion to Intervene, 1969-11-13 (Box 1)
  - Appeal from Order - CAL Staff, 1969-11-14 (Box 1)
  - Brief for Appelant - CAL Staff (Box 1)
  - Brief on Behalf of EPD (Box 1)
  - Defendants' Proposed Findings of Fact and Conclusions of Law Draft, 1969-12-11 (Box 1)
  - Plaintiff's Request for Findings of Fact and Conclusions of Law, 1969-12-19 (Box 1)
  - Defendants' Proposed Findings of Fact and Conclusion of Law, 1969-12-19 (Box 1)
  - Memorandum after Trial of the Attorney General, 1969-12-19 (Box 1)
  - Defendants' Post Trial Brief, 1969-12-22 (Box 1)
  - Trial Memo - AG (Box 1)
  - Post Trial Brief, 1969-12-29 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Cross Motion - EDP and Defendants, 1969-12-30 (Box 1)
- Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory - Personal Papers of Trustee Robert W. Purcell, 1968-1969
  - Atomic and Space Development Authority, Offers and Correspondence (Box 1)
  - "Big Four" Offers (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Offers and Solicitations of Offers to buy CAL (Box 1)
- File #5
  - Defendants' Exceptions to Plaintiff's Request for Findings of Fact and Conclusions of Law, 1970-01-02 (Box 2)
  - Reply Memo of A. G., 1970-01-02 (Box 2)
  - Reply Brief, Post Trial, 1970-01-02 (Box 2)
  - Brief for Defendants - Respondents Opposing Intervention, 1970-01-22 (Box 2)
  - Reply Brief for Appellant - CAL Tech Staff, 1970-02-05 (Box 2)
  - Decision, 1970-03-03 (Box 2)
  - Judgment, 1970-03-16 (Box 2)
  - Notice of Appeal, 1970-03-31 (Box 2)
  - CAL Tech Staff Assn. - Notice of Motion for Leave to Appeal, 1970-05-08 (Box 2)
  - Defendants' Affidavit in Opposition to Motion of CAL Tech Staff for Leave to Appeal, 1970-05-12 (Box 2)
  - CAL Tech Staff - Brief in Support of Motion for Leave to Appeal, 1970-05-15 (Box 2)
  - Syracuse University - Amicus Curiae, 1970-06-17 (Box 2)
  - CAL Tech Staff Assn. - Notice of Motion for Leave to Appeal, 1970-06-23 (Box 2)
  - CAL Tech Staff Assn. - Brief in Support of Motion for Leave to Appeal (Box 2)
- File #6
  - Brief for Appellant EDP, Appellate Division, 1970-08-07 (Box 2)
  - Affidavit and Brief in Opposition to Motion for Leave to Appeal the Denial of Intervention, 1970-09-01 (Box 2)
  - Reply Brief for Appellants, 1970-09-16 (Box 2)
  - Reply Brief for Appellants, CU and CAL - Appellate Division, 1970-09-18 (Box 2)
  - Brief for Defendants - Respondents CU and CAL - Court of Appeals, 1971-02-23 (Box 2)
  - Syracuse - Amicus Curiae Brief, Court of Appeals, 1971-03 (Box 2)
  - Brief of Defendant - Repondent EDP Tech Inc., 1971-03-12 (Box 2)
  - Brief of Appellant A.G., Court of Appeals, 1971-03 (Box 2)
  - Brief for Appellants, CU and CAL, Appellate Division, 1970-08-05 (Box 2)
- File #7
  - Transcript of Testimony, Vol. I-IV, Supreme Court, Erie County, 1969-11-17 (Box 2)
- File #8
  - Transcript of Testimony, Vol. V-VIII, Supreme Court, Erie County, 1969-11-17 (Box 2)
  - CAL - Administrative Task Force, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, Inc. B.O.D Minutes, 1958-07-1963 (Box 2)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, Inc. B.O.D Minutes, 1964-1967 (Box 2)
- File #9 - Annual Reports and Financial Statements
  - Annual Report to Board of Directors, 1947-1948 (Box 3)
  - Research Associate Program, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Annual Report to the University for Fiscal Year Ending, 1955-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1959-04-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1959-04-30 (Box 3)
  - Annual Report to Board of Directors, 1959-05 (Box 3)
  - Annual Report to the Board of Directors, 1959-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statement, 1959-08-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1959-10-31 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors Agenda, 1959-11-20 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statement, 1960-04-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1960-04-30 (Box 3)
  - Annual Report to the Board of Directors for Fiscal Year Ending, 1960-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1960-09-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statement, 1960-12-31 (Box 3)
  - Report on Research, 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statement, 1961-02-28 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statement, 1961-03-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statement, 1961-05-31 (Box 3)
  - Annual Report to the Board of Directors for Fiscal Year Ending, 1961-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1961-08-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statement, 1961-10-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1961-10-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statement, 1961-11-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statement, 1961-12-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1962-01-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1962-04-30 (Box 3)
  - Control of Indirect Costs in Research and Development, Henry K. Moffitt, 1962-06 (Box 3)
  - Financial Report of the Vice President-Controller for Fiscal Year Ending, 1965-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1962-10-31 (Box 3)
  - Report on Research, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1963-04-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Report of the Vice President-Controller for Fiscal Year Ending, 1963-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1963-08-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1963-08-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1963-10-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statement, 1963-11-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1963-11-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1963-12-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1964-01-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1964-02-29 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1964-03-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1964-04-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1964-05-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Report of the Vice President, Controller for Fiscal Year Ending, 1964-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1964-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1964-08-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1964-09-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1964-10-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1964-12 -31 (Box 3)
  - Report on Research, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1965-01-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1965-02-28 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1965-03-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1965-04-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1965-05-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1965-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Annual Fiscal Report to the President and the Trustees of Cornell for Fiscal Year Ending, 1965-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Report of the Vice President - Administration for the Fiscal Year Ending, 1966-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1966-09-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1966-12-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1967-03-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1967-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Report for Fiscal Year Ending, 1967-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1967-09-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1967-12-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1968-03-31 (Box 3)
  - Financial Charts and Data Sheets, 1968-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Report for Fiscal Year Ending, 1969-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statements, 1970-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratories, Inc. (CAL) Report: Physics Department, 1951-01-01 (Box 3)
  - CAL Report: Physics Division, 1957-08 (Box 3)
  - CAL Report: Conquering the Stratosphere, 1952 (Box 3)
  - CAL Report: Swords and Plowshares, 1955-12-02 (Box 3)
  - CAL Report: A Decade of Research, 1946-1956 (Box 3)
  - CAL Report:A Not-for-Profit Organization, Alvin E. Green, 1957-05-01 (Box 3)
  - CAL Report: A Community of Science, 1954-1967 (Box 3)
  - CAL Report: Applications of the Electron Microscope, 1960-06-01 (Box 3)
  - CAL Report: Speed of Sound Duplication in Hot-jet Simulation, John H. Hilton, Jr., 1960-10 (Box 3)
  - CAL: The Iroquois called it Buffalo, 1961 (Box 3)
  - CAL: Reports on Research, 1961-1964 (Box 3)
  - CAL Report: Control of Indirect Costs in Research and Development, Henry K. Moffitt, 1962-06 (Box 3)
  - CAL Report: Background, Capabilities and Facilities/Highway Transportation Research, 1962-10 (Box 3)
  - CAL Report: Background, Capabilities and Facilities/A General Review, 1963-06-30 (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous Files
  - Retirement Plan First Annual Report, 1958-07-01-1959-06-30 (Box 3)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, Inc. B.O.D Minutes, 1968-07-1972 (Box 4)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, Inc. By-Laws and Certificate of Incorporation (Box 4)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory - CU Relations, File I, 1967-02-1967-10 (Box 4)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory - CU Relations, File II, 1967-11-1970 (Box 4)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory - Deferred Compensation Plan (Ross), 1966-1969 (Box 4)
  - CAL-EDP Tech. Inc. - Correspondence, 1968-07-1969-12 (Box 4)
  - CAL-EDP Tech. Inc. - Correspondence, 1970-01-1971 (Box 4)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory - Fiscal Charts and Data, 1948-1955 (Box 4)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, Inc., General Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 4)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, Inc., General Correspondence, 1948-1954 (Box 4)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, Inc., General Correspondence, 1955-1963 (Box 5)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, Inc., Investigating Committees, 1966-1968 (Box 5)
  - CAL Management, File I, 1968-07-1969-12 (Box 5)
  - CAL Management File II, 1970-01-1971 (Box 5)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory - Material for Curiss Committee (Notebook), 1967-12 (Box 5)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, Inc., Minutes of Stockholder Meetings, 1960-1970 (Box 5)
  - CAL-N.Y.S. Atomic and Space Authority, 1968-1970 (Box 5)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory - News Releases, 1968-1972 (Box 5)
  - CAL - Niagara Research Institute, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - CAL - Opinions on Separation from CU (Box 5)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, Real Estate as of Nov. 20, 1968 (Box 5)
  - CAL Retirement Program, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory - Trial Report by CAL Staff (Box 5)
  - CAL - Trustee Ad Hoc Committee and CAL Structure, 1971-1973 (Box 5)
  - CAL - Trustee Minutes, 1945-1972 (Box 5)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Lab - Twentieth Anniversary Report, Organization and Background material (Box 6)
  - CALSPAN Corporation (CAL), 1972-03-01-1973-04-27 (Box 6)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Lab - Attorney General's Investigation, File I, 1968-07-1969-12 (Box 6)
  - CAL - Attorney General's Investigation, File II, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, Inc., General Correspondence, 1964-1973 (Box 6)
  - CAL Litigation - Copies of Correspondence Used for Trial (Box 6)
  - CAL-EDP Tech., Inc. - Sale Contract, Annual Reports, etc., 1968-1970 (Box 6)
  - CALSPAN Corporation (CAL) - Documents (Box 7)
  - CAL - Tax Status and Legal Aspects of Separation from CU, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory Trial Briefs, Attorney General v. CU, et al (Box 7)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory - A. G. v. Cornell, et al, Record on Appeal (Box 7)
- Chalres W. Lake - Engineering Council correspondence and reports
  - Report of the President's Study Committee on Relations between Cornell and the Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, 1967-03-27 (Box 7)
  - Report if the Faculty Council's Committee on Relations Between Cornell University and Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, 1967-03-21 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1970 (Box 7)
  - "Bidding for a Nonprofit Lab," Business Week, 1968-07-27 (Box 7)
  - Long-Range Planning: A Progress Report, 1968-05-09 (Box 7)
  - Minority Report: Curtiss Committee on CAL-CU Relations (Box 7)
  - Statement on Cornell - CAL Separation by James A. Perkins and Robert W. Purcell, 1968-05-08 (Box 7)
  - Engineering College Council Statement on Cornell-CAL Relationships - Summary, 1968-05-11 (Box 7)
  - Drafting Committee, 1968-05 (Box 7)
  - Cornell Trustee Reports, 1968-05 (Box 7)
  - Engineering College, 1968-04-1968-05 (Box 7)
  - CAL Reports, 1968-02-1968-05 (Box 7)
  - Engineering Council, 1968-05-10 (Box 7)
  - Other - Includes Chronology of Cornell-CAL Relationship Discussions, Copy of Applied Research at CAL: A Resume, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Report of the Faculty Council's Committee on Relations Between Cornell University and Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, 1967-03-21 (Box 7)
  - Report of the President's Study Committee on Relations between Cornell and the Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, 1967-03-27 (Box 7)
  - Perkin's Questions on CAL (Box 7)
  - Investigation Draft, 1968-04-24 (Box 7)
  - Agreement between EDP Technology, Inc. and Cornell University, 1969-09-02 (Box 7)
  - Exhibits to Agreement Between: Cornell University and EDP Technology, Inc., 1968-10-30 (Box 7)